Dhruv Kuchhal

Senior Research Scientist at PayPal dkuchhal@pm.me

February 3, 2024 dhruvkuchhal.com Google Scholar

ABOUT ME

I specialize in large-scale investigations of Web-based security and privacy issues. Using data-driven approaches, my work reveals the impact of real-world systems on end user security, and leads to designing better solutions. My methods include Internet/Web-wide measurements, network traffic analysis, and large-scale data mining.

INDUSTRY WORK EXPERIENCE

PayPal, Inc.

Scottsdale, AZ

Senior Research Scientist, Manager: Dr. Adam Oest.

August 2023 - Present

- Developing capabilities for risk monitoring, such as passkey fraud trends.
- Building data pipelines for scam merchant detection. Established a strategic collaboration with GASA.
- Designing solutions for early fraud alerting based on threat intelligence from Telegram.
- SME on policy issues such as Authentication and related Anti-Trust legislation in the EU.

PayPal, Inc.

Scottsdale, AZ

Information Security PhD Intern, Manager: Dr. Adam Oest.

Summers of 2021 and 2022

- Measured security characteristics of FIDO2 deployments across the Web, and combined it with internal measurements of auth systems at PayPal, to study practical risks to FIDO2 (attacks & defenses).
- Reported a bug in Google Chrome that could be exploited to trick a user enrolled in WebAuthn into authenticating an attacker-controlled sensitive action on their account. [Chromium Issue 1341134].
- Socialized findings with the various affected deployments, and received recognition from the FIDO Alliance, in terms of a security bulletin attributing the attack to our work.
- Full paper accepted and presented at ACM CCS 2023.

ACADEMIC WORK EXPERIENCE

Georgia Institute of Technology (GT)

Atlanta, GA

PhD Candidate, Advisor: Prof. Frank Li.

2019 - 2023

- (Web Privacy) Investigated privacy-invasive local network communication by websites.
- (Web Abuse) Studied dynamics of real-world view fraud campaigns.
- (Web Security) Analyzed practical security of real-world FIDO2 deployments.
- (Web Privacy) Studied the unsafe usage of WebViews to display 3rd-party web content in Android apps.

Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology

Delhi, India

Research Associate, Advisor: Prof. Ponnurangam Kumaraguru.

2017 - 2019

- Analyzed misinformation on end-to-end encrypted platforms such as WhatsApp.
- Characterized spam campaigns abusing phone numbers on online social networks.

University of Maryland, College Park

College Park, MD

Research Assistant, Advisor: Prof. Michelle Mazurek.

2018 - 2019

- Evaluated response biases in security user studies.
- Developed tools to measure the readability of security advice.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA

Doctor of Philosophy in Computer Science. Advised by Prof. Frank Li.

2019 - 2023

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University

Delhi, India

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology.

2014 - 2018

Conference

• Kuchhal, D., Ramakrishnan, K., and Li, F.,

Whatcha Lookin' At: Investigating Third-Party Web Content in Popular Android Apps. Currently under review.

• Kuchhal, D., Saad, M., Oest, A., and Li, F.,

Evaluating the Security Posture of Real-World FIDO2 Deployments.

ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), 2023.

Acceptance Rate: 19.1% (234/1222) [dl.acm.org][pdf]

• Kuchhal, D. and Li, F.,

A View into YouTube View Fraud.

ACM Web Conference (WWW), 2022.

Acceptance Rate: 17.7% (323/1822) [dl.acm.org] [pdf] [video]

• Kuchhal, D. and Li, F.,

Knock and Talk: Investigating Local Network Communications on Websites.

ACM Internet Measurement Conference (IMC), 2021.

Acceptance Rate: 27% (53/196) [dl.acm.org] [pdf] [video]

• Gupta, S., Kuchhal, D., Gupta, P., Ahamad, M., Gupta, M. and Kumaraguru, P.,

Under the Shadow of Sunshine: Characterizing Spam Campaigns Abusing Phone Numbers Across Online Social Networks*.

ACM Conference on Web Science (WebSci), 2018.

Acceptance Rate: 27% (30/113) [dl.acm.org] [pdf]

Award: Runner up for Best Student Paper

ACHIEVEMENTS/HONORS

- Y Combinator 2023: Admitted to the Summer 2023 batch (USD 500k pre-seed investment), to innovate on a GenAI-hardened replacement for CAPTCHAs on the Web.
- RSAC Security Scholar 2023: Selected among 50 cybersecurity students across US to attend the RSA Conference.
- Conference Travel Grants: Awarded funds to travel to and attend ACM CCS 2018 and PETS 2022.
- USC Annenberg Fellowship, 2019: Received a 4-year top-up fellowship to pursue a PhD in CS at USC.
- Smart India Hackathon, 2017: Our team of 6 members, advised by <u>Dr. Sambuddha Roy</u> won the first prize at India's national hackathon (10k+ students), with a cash prize of Rs. 1 lakh awarded by Government of India. [<u>GitHub</u>]
- Recognition of Service Award ACM, 2016: For serving as founding Chair for ACM-MAIT Student Chapter.

SERVICE

- PETS: External Reviewer, 2022-2023. Publication Co-Chair, 2023 and 2024. PC Member, 2024.
- ACM WebConf (WWW): PC Member, 2024.
- ACM IMC: PC Member, 2024.
- Georgia Tech School of Cybersecurity and Privacy: Member, Faculty Recruiting Committee, 2022.
- Georgia Tech Student Employee Advisory Board: Board Member, 2021-22 AY.
- Georgia Tech School of Computer Science: Founding Communications Chair of GSA, 2021-22 AY.

TECHNOLOGIES

Python, MongoDB, BigQuery, Wireshark, mitmproxy, ChromeDevTools, C++.

References

Dr. Adam Oest (Manager, PayPal; aoest@asu.edu), Prof. Frank Li (PhD Advisor, GT; frankli@gatech.edu).